June 27th
ご覧[ごらん]:(please) try to|(please) look|seeing, ニュース:news, 伝える[つたえる]:to convey/to report/to transmit
この時間 ご覧のﾆｭｰｽを
お伝えしました｡
Before we go, here are the headlines again.
テレビ:television/TV, 一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 元気[げんき]:lively/full of spirit|healthy
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]それでは 今日も一日
お元気に｡
We hope you have a great day.
Next up, News at 7.
テレビ:television/TV, 続く[つづく]:to continue|to continue (without a break)|to occur again and again||, ニュース:news
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]続いては ﾆｭｰｽ ﾏﾙﾅﾅです｡
テレビ:television/TV, 直接[ちょくせつ]:direct/immediate/personal, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]直接狙う 決めた！
He goes for the goal!
He scores!
The Japanese team have done it!
Japan Wins
日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 代表[だいひょう]:representative/representation/delegation
やってくれました 日本代表｡
テレビ:television/TV, おはようございます:good morning, 金曜日[きんようび]:Friday
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]おはようございます
今日は ６月27日 金曜日｡
Good morning. Today is Friday, June 27th.
テレビ:television/TV, 早速[さっそく]:at once/immediately/without delay, サッカー:soccer, 話題[わだい]:topic/subject, いってくる:I'm off/see you later|to go (and then come back)
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]早速 ｻｯｶｰの話題から…｡
(咲太)んじゃ いってくるな｡
Let's start with soccer.
I'll be going, then.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
(かえで)いってらっしゃい
お兄ちゃん｡
Have a nice day, Onii-chan.
日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 代表[だいひょう]:representative/representation/delegation, 勝つ[かつ]:to win/to gain victory
日本代表 勝ったか｡
Japan won, huh?
Episode 4: No Tomorrow for Pigs
寝ぐせ[ねぐせ, ねグセ]:bed hair/hair disarranged during sleep|habit of moving around in one's sleep, 立つ[たつ]:to stand|to find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)|to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)
(国見)うっす 咲太
寝ぐせ立ってるぞ｡
'Sup, Sakuta. Some bedhead you've got there.
ヘアスタイル:hairstyle, 斬新[ざんしん]:novel/original/newness
これは そういうﾍｱｽﾀｲﾙなんだよ｡
斬新だな｡
It's a hairstyle.
That's a new one.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
おっ 双葉も うっす｡
(理央)おはよ…｡
And 'sup, Futaba.
Morning.
Japan won. Did you see the free kick in the first half?
日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 代表[だいひょう]:representative/representation/delegation, 勝つ[かつ]:to win/to gain victory
日本代表 勝ったな｡
前半[ぜんはん, ぜんぱん]:first half, フリーキック:free kick, 朝[あさ, あした]:morning, 朝[ちょう]:dynasty|reign|period||, ニュース:news
前半のﾌﾘｰｷｯｸ 見たか？
ああ 朝のﾆｭｰｽで見た｡
Yeah. I caught it on the morning news.
スポーツ:sport/sports, オンタイム:on time/punctually
ｽﾎﾟｰﾂはｵﾝﾀｲﾑで見ないと
騒げないぞ｡
You gotta watch sports live.
It's more exciting that way.
そっか｡
Is it?
作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
本当に作ったんだ｡
You really made me lunch?
Hey, I did it because you were being all sassy, like, "Can you even cook, Mai-san?"
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 料理[りょうり]:cooking/cookery|dealing with something, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
(麻衣)咲太が ｢麻衣さんって
料理できんの？｣なんて
生意気[なまいき]:impertinent/saucy/cheeky, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
生意気なこと言うから
作ってきてあげたんでしょ｡
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
すみませんでした｡
僕が悪かったです｡
Okay, that was my bad.
生意気[なまいき]:impertinent/saucy/cheeky, なさる:to do
生意気でした ごめんなさい｡
わかればいいのよ｡
I was too cheeky. Sorry.
As long as you understand.
いただく:to receive/to get|to eat
いただきます｡
Let's eat.
Yes, let's.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
あの… 麻衣さん｡
何よ？
Uh, Mai-san.
What?
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
好きです つきあってください｡
I love you. Please go out with me.
無視[むし]:disregarding/ignoring
え 無視？
You're ignoring that?
After hearing that every day for a month,
I don't feel anything anymore.
か月[かげつ]:months (period of), 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense
１か月間 同じこと言われてると
何も感じなくなる｡
ときめく:to throb/to flutter/to palpitate, ときめく:to be prosperous/to prosper/to flourish, ひどい:cruel/heartless|violent
ときめかない｡
言わせておいて ひどいな｡
My heart doesn't skip a beat.
That's harsh. You're the one who made me say it.
放送[ほうそう]:broadcast/broadcasting, ドラマ:drama, 出演[しゅつえん]:performance/stage appearance|to act (in a play), 決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
そうだ ７月放送のﾄﾞﾗﾏに
出演が決まったの｡
Oh, right.
I've been cast in a TV show starting in July.
深夜[しんや]:late at night, 枠[わく]:frame|border|limit, 中盤[ちゅうばん]:middle (stage), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 登場[とうじょう]:entry (on stage)/appearance (on screen)|entrance, 役[えき, えだち]:war/campaign|unpaid work (ritsuryo system), 役[やく]:use|post|scoring combination (e.g. in mahjong, card games, etc.)
深夜枠で中盤の１話にだけ
登場する役なんだけどね｡
Though it's a late-night slot, and I'm only appearing in an episode in the middle.
キスシーン:kiss scene
ｷｽｼｰﾝもあるんだから｡
There's even a kiss scene.
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
キスシーン:kiss scene
今 なんて？
ｷｽｼｰﾝがあるの｡
What did you just say?
There's a kiss scene.
Turn it down.
断る[ことわる]:to refuse|to inform|to ask leave, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
断ってください｡
いいじゃない｡
What's the big deal? Not like it'll be my first.
初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
初めてってわけでもないし｡
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
ちょっと待った 麻衣さん
初めてじゃないって…｡
Hang on.
What do you mean, it won't be your first?
ファーストキス:first kiss, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair), 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|
私のﾌｧｰｽﾄｷｽ 咲太にあげたの
覚えてないの？
Don't you remember how I gave you my first kiss?
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
最低[さいてい]:least|worst|awful|, まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected
最低｡
え？ まさか
You're the worst.
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
Huh? Was it when I'd forgotten about you?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room
僕が麻衣さんを忘れていた
あの間に？
おとぎ話[おとぎばなし]:fairy-tale/nursery-tale, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
おとぎ話みたいにはいかないわね｡
It doesn't work like in fairy tales, huh?
ｷｽをすれば 咲太が私のことを
I thought you'd remember me if I kissed you.
思い出す[おもいだす]:to recall/to remember/to recollect
思い出してくれると
思ったんだけどな｡
必ず[かならず]:always/without exception/necessarily, 思い出す[おもいだす]:to recall/to remember/to recollect, 詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well, 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho
必ず思い出すので
詳しい時間と場所を
Tell me when and where it happened.
I swear I'll remember it.
教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
教えてください｡
嫌よ｡
No way.
At least give me a hint.
ヒント:hint, 絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
ﾋﾝﾄだけでも｡
絶対に教えない｡
Never.
そこをなんとか…｡
じゃあ…｡
Please!
Want to do it again, then?
一回[いっかい]:once/one time/one round
もう一回する？
ぜひ…｡
I'd love to.
目を閉じる[めをとじる]:to close one's eyes/to lower one's eyelids|to die
目を閉じて｡
Close your eyes.
いくわね｡
Here I go.
本当にされると思ったんだ｡
You really thought I'd do it?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 間接[かんせつ]:indirection/indirectness, うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
麻衣さんと間接ｷｽができて
うれしいなぁ｡
I'm so happy I got to have an indirect kiss with you.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 大人[おとな, だいにん]:adult, 大人[たいじん]:man of substance or virtue|giant|adult, 年下[としした]:younger/junior, 間接[かんせつ]:indirection/indirectness, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
まっ 麻衣さんは大人だし
年下の僕と間接ｷｽするくらい
Well, I'm sure a mature lady such as yourself
would think nothing of indirectly kissing a younger boy.
なんともないんだろうけど｡
そ そうね｡
Th-That's right.
Just so you know, it's not me.
言っておくけど 私じゃないから｡
キスシーン:kiss scene, 主演[しゅえん]:starring/playing the leading part
ん？
ｷｽｼｰﾝがあるのは主演の子｡
The kiss scene is for the lead actress.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 性格[せいかく]:character/personality/disposition, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
麻衣さん 性格悪すぎ｡
You're a bully, you know that?
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
でも咲太は そんな私のことが
好きなんでしょ｡
But that's what you like about me, right?
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger, 愛[あい]:love/affection|attachment, 愛[まな]:beloved/dear, 冷める[さめる]:to become cool (e.g. from a high temperature to room temperature)/to come down (fever)|to cool down (interest)
さすがに このままだと
愛が冷めそう｡
I can feel myself falling out of love by the minute.
なっ なんでよ！
Wh-Why?
I mean, you don't seem interested at all.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
だって 麻衣さん
全然その気なさそうだし
ときめく:to throb/to flutter/to palpitate, ときめく:to be prosperous/to prosper/to flourish, 絶望的[ぜつぼうてき]:desperate/hopeless, 気分[きぶん]:feeling/mood
ときめかないとか言われると
絶望的な気分になる｡
And when you say you don't feel anything, it makes me lose all hope.
ﾀﾞﾒとは言ってない｡
Hey, I didn't say no.
Will you go out with me, then?
じゃあ いいの？
それは その…｡
Well, uh...
My
Neighbor,
the
Whimsical
Prince
of
Sweets
My Neighbor,
the
Whimsical
Prince
of
Sweets
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
いいの？
Is that a yes?
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
Yes.
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
うん いいよ｡
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
Let's go out.
What's gotten into you, Onii-chan?
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
どうしたんですか？ お兄ちゃん｡
何でもない｡
Nothing. It's just, waiting a month paid off.
か月[かげつ]:months (period of)
１か月待ったかいが
あったってことだ｡
晴れる[はれる]:to clear up|to refresh (e.g. spirits)|to be cleared (e.g. of a suspicion)|, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
今日から 晴れて
僕と麻衣さんは…｡
Mai-san and I are now...
The Japanese team have done it!
Japan Wins
日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 代表[だいひょう]:representative/representation/delegation
やってくれました 日本代表｡
テレビ:television/TV, おはようございます:good morning, 金曜日[きんようび]:Friday
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]おはようございます
今日は ６月27日 金曜日｡
Good morning. Today is Friday, June 27th.
June 27th
テレビ:television/TV, 早速[さっそく]:at once/immediately/without delay, サッカー:soccer, 話題[わだい]:topic/subject
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]早速 ｻｯｶｰの話題から
いきたいと思います｡
Let's start with soccer.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
どうしたんですか？ お兄ちゃん｡
なぁ かえで
What's the matter, Onii-chan?
Hey, Kaede. This may be a weird question, but...
ニュース:news, 昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday
ﾍﾝなこと聞くけどさ
このﾆｭｰｽ 昨日も見たよな？
Didn't we watch this same report yesterday?
えっと:let me see/well/errr ...
えっと… 見てませんけど？
Uh... I know I didn't.
寝ぐせ[ねぐせ, ねグセ]:bed hair/hair disarranged during sleep|habit of moving around in one's sleep, 立つ[たつ]:to stand|to find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)|to depart (on a plane, train, etc.), 髪型[かみがた]:hair style/coiffure/hairdo
うっす 咲太 寝ぐせ立ってるぞ｡
これは そういう髪型なんだよ｡
'Sup, Sakuta. Some bedhead you've got there.
It's a hairstyle.
斬新[ざんしん]:novel/original/newness, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
斬新だな｡ おっ 双葉も うっす｡
おはよ…｡
That's a new one.
And 'sup, Futaba.
Morning.
What's wrong, Sakuta?
会話[かいわ]:conversation, 昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday
どうした 咲太？
この会話 昨日もしなかったか？
Didn't we have the same conversation yesterday?
いや してないと思うぞ｡ なぁ？
Nah, I don't think we did.
Right?
してないね｡
だよな なら いいんだ｡
We didn't.
I guess not. Forget it.
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance
《もしかして
僕だけってことか…》
Is it just me?
数式[すうしき]:numerical formula
という数式から わかるわけだ｡
This formula will give you the solution.
授業[じゅぎょう]:lesson/class work/teaching
《この授業も
This class,
ワイシャツ:shirt/business shirt/dress shirt, 口紅[くちべに]:lipstick, 跡[あと]:trace|site|scar, 跡[せき]:trace
あのﾜｲｼｬﾂの口紅の跡も…》
that lipstick on his shirt...
That's newlyweds for you.
重力[じゅうりょく]:gravity/gravitation/gravitational pull, 加速度[かそくど]:acceleration, 場合[ばあい]:case/situation
重力加速度をﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ…
じゃなかった Ｇとした場合…｡
Let's refer to the gravitational acceleration as the G-Unit—
or rather, G—
...and the teacher's lame jokes
are all the same as yesterday.
寒い[さむい, さぶい]:cold (e.g. weather)|uninteresting (esp. joke)/lame, ギャグ:joke/gag, 昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
《この寒いｷﾞｬｸﾞも昨日と同じ｡
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday
今日が昨日ってことなら
If today is yesterday, then Mai-san and I aren't going out yet.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, 段階[だんかい]:grade/level/stage, 段階[きざはし, きだはし]:stairs|stairs at the front of a noh stage
麻衣さんと僕も
まだつきあう前の段階｡
ってことは…》
Which means...
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
好きです つきあってください｡
I love you. Please go out with me.
か月[かげつ]:months (period of), 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense
１か月間 同じこと言われると
何も感じなくなる｡
After hearing that every day for a month,
I don't feel anything anymore.
ときめく:to throb/to flutter/to palpitate, ときめく:to be prosperous/to prosper/to flourish, 失恋[しつれん]:disappointed love/broken heart/unrequited love
ときめかない｡
そっか 失恋か｡
My heart doesn't skip a beat.
I see. I'm being rejected, huh?
新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, 恋[こい]:(romantic) love, 探す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
じゃあ
新しい恋を探すしかないな｡
I guess I'll have to find a new love.
今まで[いままで]:until now/so far/up to the present, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, ござる:to be
え？ ちょっ…｡
今まで ありがとうございました｡
Huh? Wai—
Thank you for everything.
諦める[あきらめる]:to give up/to abandon (hope, plans)/to resign oneself (to)
ﾀﾞﾒとは言ってない｡
なに諦めようとしてるのよ｡
H-Hey, I didn't say no.
Why are you just giving up?
なら いいの？
Will you go out with me, then?
生意気[なまいき]:impertinent/saucy/cheeky
咲太のくせに生意気…｡
You're too cheeky, Sakuta.
いいの？
Is that a yes?
うん いいよ…｡
Yes. Let's go out.
問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
ふぅ… これで問題なし｡
Okay. It's all good now.
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other
(前沢)あのさ よかったら
俺とつきあわない？
Hey, what say you go out with me?
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
(朋絵)え？
(前沢)嫌かな？
You don't wanna?
い いえ その…｡
I-It's not like that.
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, させる:to make (someone) do|to allow (someone) to, させる:(usu. followed by a negative form) worth special consideration, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
(朋絵)あの…
少し考えさせてください｡
Um...
Give me some time to think about it.
Another budding romance, huh?
告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
《こっちも告白か｡
晴れる[はれる]:to clear up|to refresh (e.g. spirits)|to be cleared (e.g. of a suspicion)|, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart, 同士[どうし, どし]:fellow/mutual/companion
僕も晴れて麻衣さんと恋人同士｡
Mai-san and I have become a couple, too.
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 完璧[かんぺき, かんべき]:perfect/complete/flawless
あとは明日さえ来れば完璧》
Now as long as tomorrow comes, it'll all be perfect.
The Japanese team have done it!
テレビ:television/TV, 日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 代表[だいひょう]:representative/representation/delegation
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]やってくれました 日本代表｡
おはようございます:good morning, 金曜日[きんようび]:Friday
おはようございます
今日は ６月27日 金曜日｡
Japan Wins
Good morning. Today is Friday, June 27th.
テレビ:television/TV, 早速[さっそく]:at once/immediately/without delay, サッカー:soccer, 話題[わだい]:topic/subject
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]早速 ｻｯｶｰの話題から
いきたいと思います｡
Let's start with soccer.
またか…｡
ん？
Not again.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
何が またなんですか？
お兄ちゃん｡
What are you not-again-ing, Onii-chan?
June 27th
Nothing. Never mind.
いや なんでもない｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
これは双葉に相談だな｡
I'm gonna have to talk to Futaba about this.
病[やまい]:illness/disease|bad habit, 病[いたずき, いたつき]:pain/trouble|illness
(理央)梓川 それ 中２病だよ｡
Physics Prep Room
Azusagawa...
That only happens in children's imaginations.
高[たか, だか]:quantity/amount/volume, 高[こう]:high school|high-, 病[やまい]:illness/disease|bad habit, 病[いたずき, いたつき]:pain/trouble|illness
僕は高２だ｡
なら 高２病でいいや｡
I think I'm past that age.
You've raised the bar to adolescents, then.
大好き[だいすき]:loveable/very likeable/like very much, 思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty, 症候群[しょうこうぐん]:syndrome
そうでなければ 梓川の大好きな
思春期症候群なんじゃないの｡
If not that, then maybe it's your beloved Puberty Syndrome again?
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
これっぽっちも好きじゃない｡
I don't love it at all.
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 困る[こまる]:to be troubled/to be worried/to be bothered
てか なんとかしてくれ｡
明日が来なくて困ってるんだ｡
Do something about this.
Tomorrow just won't come. It sucks.
梓川が自分で
なんとかするしかないでしょ｡
You'll have to figure something out yourself.
含める[ふくめる]:to include (in a group or scope)|to instruct|to include (a nuance)||, 他[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 他[た]:other (esp. people and abstract matters), 億[おく]:10^8/100,000,000/hundred million, 人類[じんるい]:mankind/humanity
私も含めて
その他70億人の人類は
The other seven billion people
on this planet, me included,
度目[どめ]:the Nth time, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
今日が３度目なんて
思ってないから｡
are not living today for the third time.
June 27th Repeating Third Time
Your search did not match any documents.
Please. Think of it as doing me a favor.
人助け[ひとだすけ]:act of mercy/helping another person
そこをなんとか
人助けと思って｡
ループ:loop/ring network
梓川は 時間がﾙｰﾌﾟしてるって
言うけど
You say you're stuck in a time loop,
考え[かんがえ]:thinking|idea|intention||, とらわれる:to be caught/to be captured|to be seized with (fear, etc.)
その考えには
とらわれないほうが
but you probably shouldn't be beholden to that idea.
いいんじゃない？
なんで？
Why not?
Because it's all kinds of hard to go back to the past.
過去[かこ]:the past|a past (i.e. a personal history one would prefer remained secret)|past (tense)|, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from, いろいろ:various|various colors (colours), 大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||
過去に戻るのは
いろいろと大変だから｡
何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?, 経験[けいけん]:experience
梓川が何度か経験した
６月27日は
The June 27th that you've
lived through multiple times
未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
それより前の時間から
未来を見たものかもしれない｡
might just be you seeing it
from an earlier point in time.
過去[かこ]:the past|a past (i.e. a personal history one would prefer remained secret)|past (tense)|, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from, 大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer
過去に戻るのが大変なら
未来へ行くのは もっと大変だろ｡
If going to the past is hard,
shouldn't going to the future be even harder?
タイムトラベル:time travel, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, 予知[よち]:foresight/foreknowledge/intimation, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
ﾀｲﾑﾄﾗﾍﾞﾙじゃなくて
未来予知って意味｡
I'm talking about precognition, not time travel.
未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, 予知[よち]:foresight/foreknowledge/intimation, 簡単[かんたん]:simple/easy|brief
いや 未来予知も
簡単じゃないだろ｡
Uh, that's not very simple either.
悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔って 聞いたことない？
Have you ever heard of Laplace's demon?
あいにく:unfortunately/Sorry, but ..., 悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra, 知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance
あいにく
悪魔の知り合いはいないな｡
Sadly, I don't have any demonic acquaintances.
世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being, あらゆる:all/every, 物質[ぶっしつ]:material/substance|matter
この世界に存在する
あらゆる物質は
All matter in this universe is equally bound under universal laws.
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 物理[ぶつり]:physics/law of nature, 法則[ほうそく]:law/rule, 支配下[しはいか]:under control (e.g. of territory), 平等[びょうどう]:equality/impartiality/evenness
同じ物理法則の支配下に
平等である｡
法則[ほうそく]:law/rule, 数式[すうしき]:numerical formula, 化[か]:action of making something/-ification, 計算[けいさん]:calculation/reckoning|forecast, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
その法則を数式化して
計算してしまえば
If you turn those laws into an equation that you can solve,
未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, 状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 導き出す[みちびきだす]:to draw (conclusion)/to deduce/to derive
未来の状況を導き出せる｡
you can predict the future.
まるで:quite/entirely|as if, ピンとくる:to get (a joke or explanation)/to strike home/to know intuitively
まるでﾋﾟﾝとこない｡
I'm not sure I follow.
世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being, 原子[げんし]:atom, 位置[いち]:place/situation/position
つまり この世界に存在する
すべての原子の位置と
Long story short,
if one were to know the precise location and momentum of every atom in the universe,
運動量[うんどうりょう]:momentum|amount of exercise
運動量がわかれば…｡
未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, 状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 計算[けいさん]:calculation/reckoning|forecast, 導き出す[みちびきだす]:to draw (conclusion)/to deduce/to derive
未来の状況を 計算によって
導き出せるってことだよ｡
their future values could be calculated using the laws of classical mechanics.
原子[げんし]:atom, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 数[しばしば]:often/again and again/frequently, 数[かず]:number/amount
すべての原子って すごい数だろ｡
Every atom in the universe?
That's an astronomical number.
膨大[ぼうだい]:huge/vast|swelling, データ:data/datum, 数式[すうしき]:numerical formula, 計算[けいさん]:calculation/reckoning|forecast
うん 膨大なﾃﾞｰﾀを
数式で計算するとなれば
Yeah.
Running all that data through an equation would require considerable time.
相応[そうおう]:suitability/fitness, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
それ相応の時間が必要となる｡
秒[びょう]:second (60th min), 後[あと]:behind|after|after one's death||, 後[のち]:later|future|after one's death|, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, 計算[けいさん]:calculation/reckoning|forecast, 以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||, かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
１秒後の未来を計算するのに
１秒以上かかったんじゃ
It'd be pointless to calculate one second into the future if it took more than a second to do so.
意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
意味がない｡
だよな｡
Right?
途方[とほう]:way/destination/reason, 真似[まね, マネ]:imitating/copying|behavior
だから そんな途方もない
真似ができる
So a physicist, Laplace, came up with a fictional being who could do that.
空想[くうそう]:daydream/fantasy/fancy, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being, 物理学[ぶつりがく]:physics
空想上の存在を
物理学者のﾗﾌﾟﾗｽさんは
考え出す[かんがえだす]:to think out/to devise/to invent, 悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
考え出した｡
それがﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔か｡
And that's Laplace's demon, huh?
悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra, 一瞬[いっしゅん]:instant/moment/for an instant, 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being
その悪魔には
一瞬で この世界に存在する
It has the ability to know the location
and momentum of every atom in existence
原子[げんし]:atom, 位置[いち]:place/situation/position, 運動量[うんどうりょう]:momentum|amount of exercise, 把握[はあく]:grasp/catch/understanding
すべての原子の位置と運動量を
把握する力があって
and can calculate the future in an instant.
瞬時[しゅんじ]:moment/instant, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, 計算[けいさん]:calculation/reckoning|forecast
瞬時に未来を計算できる｡
計算[けいさん]:calculation/reckoning|forecast, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come
僕が今 見ているのも
そうやって計算した未来だと？
And what I'm living now is a
calculation of the future too?
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
そう｡
悪いが 僕は
Right.
I hate to break it to you,
but I'm not some shady demon.
怪しい[あやしい]:suspicious/dubious|charming, 悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
そんな怪しげな悪魔じゃないぞ｡
本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal, 悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra, 捜す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
だったら 本物のﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔を
捜すんだね｡
Then you'll have to find the real Laplace's demon.
And how do I do that?
悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
どうやって？
悪魔だけは
The demon is likely the only one aware of the looping June 27th
繰り返す[くりかえす]:to repeat/to do something over again, 記憶[きおく]:memory/recollection|storage, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
繰り返される６月27日の記憶を
持ったまま
前回[ぜんかい]:previous time/last time/previous installment, 行動[こうどう]:action/conduct/behaviour, 可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility
前回とは違う行動を
とってる可能性が
and therefore the only one acting differently from loop to loop.
高い[たかい]:high/tall|expensive
高いんじゃない？
前回[ぜんかい]:previous time/last time/previous installment, 行動[こうどう]:action/conduct/behaviour
《前回と違った行動を
とってるやつ…》
Someone acting differently from previous loops...
重力[じゅうりょく]:gravity/gravitation/gravitational pull, 加速度[かそくど]:acceleration
重力加速度をﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ…｡
Let's refer to the gravitational acceleration—
How the hell am I supposed to pick them out
from the seven billion people in this world?
全[ぜん]:all/whole|pan-, 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 億[おく]:10^8/100,000,000/hundred million, 人類[じんるい]:mankind/humanity
《そんなの 全世界70億いる
人類の中から
見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing
見つけられるわけないだろ｡
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 昼[ひる]:noon|daytime|lunch, 唯一[ゆいいつ, ゆいつ]:only/sole/unique, 癒やし[いやし]:healing/soothing/therapy
麻衣さんとのお昼の時間だけが
唯一の癒やしだよな…》
Lunchtime with Mai-san is my only solace.
悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
いたよ ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔｡
Wow, I actually found Laplace's demon.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
梓川先輩… だよね？
You're Azusagawa-senpai, right?
年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year
梓川咲太 ２年生｡
古賀朋絵 １年生… です｡
Azusagawa Sakuta, second-year.
Koga Tomoe, first-year. Pleased to meet you.
タメ口[タメぐち, ためぐち]:casual talk/frank, unreserved speech/peer language, 尻[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 尻[しり]:buttocks|undersurface|last place|, 蹴る[ける]:to kick|to refuse/to reject, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|, 仲[なか]:relation/relationship, 仲[すあい, すわい]:broker/brokerage/brokerage fee
ﾀﾒ口でいい
尻を蹴り合った仲なんだし｡
No need to be so formal.
We're butt-kicking buddies.
忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of
それ 忘れて！
古賀 つかぬことを聞くが｡
Forget about that!
Koga, can I ask you something random?
何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?
何？
今日は何度目だ？
What?
How many times does today make?
It's my third time.
度目[どめ]:the Nth time
僕は３度目だ｡
It's my third time too.
度目[どめ]:the Nth time
私も３度目…｡
私だけじゃなかったんだ｡
So it wasn't just me.
この先[このさき]:beyond this point/from now on/after this
何なの？ これ
この先 どげんなると？
What's happening?
What's gonna become of me?
Teenage Pig Doesn't
Dream of Bunny Girls
一応[いちおう]:more or less|tentatively|just in case|, 心当たり[こころあたり]:having in mind/happening to know of/idea
一応 聞くけど
古賀に心当たりはないのか？
Just to be sure, do you have any idea why this might be happening?
いっちょんわからん｡
何だって？
Not an inklin'.
Say what?
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
あっ… ぜ 全然わかんない｡
N-No idea.
使える[つかえる]:to be usable/to be serviceable/to be useful, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, じゃん:isn't it
使えねえ｡
それ 先輩じゃん！
Useless.
Right back at you!
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant, 悩む[なやむ]:to be worried/to be troubled
なんか最近 嫌なこととか
悩んでることないか？
Did something bad happen recently? Is there anything troubling you?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good
なんで そんなこと
先輩に言わないといけないの？
Why should I have to tell you that?
メッセージ:message
あっ ﾒｯｾｰｼﾞ｡
(受信音)
Oh, I've got a message.
Because I'm pretty sure
Puberty Syndrome is involved here.
状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty, 症候群[しょうこうぐん]:syndrome
この状況
思春期症候群だと思うからな｡
思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty, 特有[とくゆう]:characteristic (of)/peculiar (to), 不安定[ふあんてい]:instability/insecurity/crankiness, 精神[せいしん]:mind/soul/heart
古賀の思春期特有の
不安定な精神が
If a classic teenage instability of yours is what's behind this,
引き起こす[ひきおこす]:to cause/to induce|to pull upright, 状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances
引き起こしている状況なら
原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source, 究明[きゅうめい]:investigation (esp. in academic and scientific contexts), 解消[かいしょう]:cancellation/liquidation/resolution
その原因を究明して
解消するしかない｡
then we'll have to figure out
the cause and resolve it.
思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty, 症候群[しょうこうぐん]:syndrome, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 正気[しょうき]:sanity/consciousness/soberness, 正気[せいき]:true character/true heart/true spirit
思春期症候群って 先輩 正気？
Puberty Syndrome? Are you serious, Senpai?
ネット:network, うわさ:rumour/rumor/report, じゃん:isn't it
そんなのﾈｯﾄのうわさじゃん｡
That's just an online rumor.
Stop doing that while you're talking to me.
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), 最中[さいちゅう, さなか]:in the middle of/height of/in course of, 最中[もなか]:wafer cake filled with bean jam, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, 返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
てか 話してる最中は やめろ｡
返してよ！
Hey, give it back!
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), ながら:while/during|while
話しながらは しないから！
Okay, I won't text and talk at the same time!
ほれ｡
Here.
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, 気が散る[きがちる]:to get distracted/to jump off the track, 話しかける[はなしかける]:to address (someone)/to accost a person|to begin to talk
話すほうをやめんのか？
気が散る 話しかけないで｡
So you chose to stop talking?
Quiet. You're distracting me.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 女子高生[じょしこうせい]:female high-school student
すげえな 女子高生｡
High school girls are something else.
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
で なに？
最近 嫌なこととか
Okay, where were we?
Did something bad happen recently?
Is there anything troubling you?
悩む[なやむ]:to be worried/to be troubled
悩んでることはないか？
That might be a hint to getting past June 27th.
抜け出す[ぬけだす]:to slip out/to sneak away|to break (out of a loop), ヒント:hint, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
６月27日を抜け出すﾋﾝﾄが
そこにあるかもしれない｡
I've put on some weight.
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 太る[ふとる]:to grow fat (stout, plump)/to become fat/to gain weight
少し太った｡
大丈夫だ｡
That's okay. If anything, you're too thin.
むしろ:rather/better/instead, むしろ:woven mat (esp. one made of straw)|seat, 痩せる[やせる]:to become thin/to lose weight|to be barren
古賀は むしろ痩せている｡
It'd do you good to gain some weight,
especially around the chest area.
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 太る[ふとる]:to grow fat (stout, plump)/to become fat/to gain weight, ぺったんこ:crushed flat/flattened|flat-chested girl, 胸[むね, むな]:chest|breasts|heart||
少し太って
そのぺったんこな胸に
肉[にく, しし]:flesh|meat|the physical body (as opposed to the spirit)||, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, 全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, お尻[おしり, オシリ]:bottom/buttocks, お腹[おなか]:belly/abdomen/stomach
肉をつけたほうがいいくらいだ｡
全部 お尻とお腹にいくから
It all goes to my waist and butt!
That's why it sucks!
困る[こまる]:to be troubled/to be worried/to be bothered
困ってるの｡
(足音)
隠れる[かくれる]:to hide/to be hidden/to conceal oneself
あっ 隠れて！
おっ｡
H-Hide!
Is he looking for you?
捜す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
古賀を捜してるんじゃないのか？
そうだと思うけど
Probably, but I texted him and said I had something to do over lunch break.
昼休み[ひるやすみ]:lunch break/noon recess/noon rest period, 用事[ようじ]:tasks/things to do/errand, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target, メッセージ:message, 送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||
昼休みは用事がある的な
ﾒｯｾｰｼﾞを送っちゃったし｡
ﾊｧ…｡
いいから さっさと
Just go let him ask you out.
告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
告白されてこい｡
なして 告白のこと知っとおと？
How'd ya know 'bout that?
I saw it last time.
前回[ぜんかい]:previous time/last time/previous installment, そもそも:in the first place/to begin with|... the heck (e.g. "what the heck?"), 隠れる[かくれる]:to hide/to be hidden/to conceal oneself, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
前回 見たんだよ｡ そもそも
なんで隠れる必要があるんだ？
Why do you even need to hide from him?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 憧れ[あこがれ]:yearning/longing/aspiration
だって 前沢先輩は
玲奈ちゃんの憧れの人なんだよ？
Because Maesawa-senpai is Rena-chan's crush.
クラス:class, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
はぁ？
ｸﾗｽの友達 香芝玲奈ちゃん｡
What?
Kashiba Rena. My friend in class.
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, バスケ:basketball, 練習[れんしゅう]:practice/practising
よく一緒に ﾊﾞｽｹ部の練習を
見に行ってたの｡
We often went together to watch the basketball team practice.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, かっこいい:attractive/good-looking/stylish
(朋絵)玲奈ちゃんが
｢前沢先輩かっこいい！｣って
Rena-chan said she thought
Maesawa-senpai was hot,
付き添う[つきそう]:to attend on/to wait upon/to accompany
言ってて 私は それに
付き添ってただけなんだけど｡
and I was only tagging along with her...
気に入る[きにいる]:to be pleased with/to suit
古賀のほうが気に入られたと？
う うん｡
But he took a liking to you instead?
Y-Yeah.
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), ううん:no|er, well, ...
お前も その人のこと好きなわけ？
ううん｡
Do you like him back?
Nah. I ain't got a thing for the popular sorts.
モテる:to be popular (esp. with the opposite sex)/to be well liked/to be pampered (spoiled, doted upon, etc.), 好く[すく]:to like/to love/to be fond of, 好く[よく]:nicely/properly|frequently
ﾓﾃそうな人は いっちょん好かん｡
Then why don't you just let him ask you out and turn him down?
告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
だったら さっさと告白されて
ふればいいだろ｡
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, クラス:class
そんなことしたら
絶対にｸﾗｽでﾊﾌﾞられる！
But if I did, I'd definitely become the class outcast!
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
玲奈ちゃんの…
友達の好きな人なんだよ｡
Rena-chan... My friend has a crush on him, y'know?
告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional), 空気[くうき]:air|mood|someone with no presence, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
なのに 私が告白されるとか
空気読めてなさすぎ！
How am I supposed to let him ask me out?
I'm not that clueless!
大声[おおごえ, たいせい]:loud voice, バレる:to leak out (a secret)/to be exposed (a lie, improper behaviour, etc.) (behavior)
大声出すとﾊﾞﾚる｡
Keep it down. He'll hear you.
用事[ようじ]:tasks/things to do/errand, 趣味[しゅみ]:hobby/pastime|tastes, 悪[あく]:evil/wickedness, 悪[わる]:bad thing/bad person
用事って これかよ
男の趣味 悪っ｡
So "something to do" meant someone to do, huh?
Damn, you have awful taste.
違い[ちがい]:difference/discrepancy
いや 違い…｡
あっ あっ…｡
No, it's not—
誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding
これは誤解です｡
This isn't what it looks like.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 説明[せつめい]:explanation/exposition, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
待って 麻衣さん
説明をさせてください！
Wait, Mai-san!
Let me explain!
話しかける[はなしかける]:to address (someone)/to accost a person|to begin to talk
話しかけないで｡
Don't talk to me.
Whatever.
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, やり直す[やりなおす]:to do over again/to redo/to start over
まっ いっか どうせ明日も
今日をやり直すんだろうしな｡
It'll all be reset tomorrow, anyway.
Good morning.
Whodunnit?!
おはようございます:good morning, 土曜日[どようび]:Saturday
おはようございます
今日は ６月28日 土曜日｡
Today is Saturday, June 28th.
テレビ:television/TV, 驚き[おどろき, オドロキ]:surprise/astonishment/wonder, ニュース:news, 伝える[つたえる]:to convey/to report/to transmit
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]驚きのﾆｭｰｽから
お伝えしたいと思います｡
Let's start with this shocking report.
June 28th
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
どうかしましたか？ お兄ちゃん｡
かえで
What's the matter, Onii-chan?
Kaede, please pinch my cheek for me.
ほっぺた:cheek, つねる:to pinch
僕のほっぺたをつねってくれ｡
はい わかりました｡
Sure thing.
痛い[いたい]:painful/sore|exceeding
痛いな｡
Okay, that hurts.
What do you want on this fine Saturday morning?
土曜[どよう]:Saturday, 朝っぱら[あさっぱら]:early morning, タイムマシン:time machine, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
土曜の朝っぱらから なに？
[℡]ﾀｲﾑﾏｼﾝを作ってくれ｡
Build me a time machine.
切る[きる]:to cut|to sever (connections, ties)|to turn off (e.g. the light)||, いたって:very much/exceedingly/extremely, 大[おお]:big/large, 大[だい]:the large part of|big|approximate size||, まじめ:diligent/serious/honest
切っていい？
僕はいたって大まじめだ｡
Can I hang up now?
I'm completely serious.
着替える[きがえる, きかえる]:to change one's clothes
[℡]今 着替え中なんだけど｡
I'm getting dressed here.
具体的[ぐたいてき]:concrete/tangible/definite, どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
具体的に どんな状況か
教えてくれ｡
Tell me more. What stage are you at?
靴下[くつした]:socks/sock/stockings, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different, 順番[じゅんばん]:turn (in line)/order of things/sequential order, 着替える[きがえる, きかえる]:to change one's clothes
[℡]あと靴下をはくだけ｡
変わった順番で着替えるのな｡
Just need to slip on my socks.
Socks last? That's a strange order.
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, 用件[ようけん]:business/thing to be done/something that should be performed
普通でしょ で 用件は？
It's normal.
So what do you want?
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|
[℡]昨日 相談したこと
覚えてるよな？
Remember the talk yesterday
about being stuck in the same day?
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 繰り返す[くりかえす]:to repeat/to do something over again, めでる:to love/to admire
[℡]同じ日を繰り返してるってやつ｡
おめでと｡
Congrats.
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 脱出[だっしゅつ]:escape/break-out|prolapse, 不本意[ふほんい]:reluctant/unwilling/involuntary, かたち:form/shape|visage
[℡]昨日を脱出できたんだ｡
不本意なかたちでな｡
You made it out of yesterday like you wanted.
I did want it, but not like this.
靴下[くつした]:socks/sock/stockings
[℡]それじゃ 私 靴下はくから｡
(通話が切れる音)
I'm putting on my socks. Bye.
靴下[くつした]:socks/sock/stockings, 以下[いか, いげ]:not exceeding|below (e.g. standard)|the below-mentioned
僕は靴下以下か｡
Socks are more important than me?
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday
《とにかく
昨日が もう来ないなら
Anyway, if I can't go back to yesterday,
I'll have to clear the air with Mai-san and have her forgive me.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, 解く[とく]:to untie|to unsew|to solve||, 解く[ほどく]:to unfasten/to untie/to unwrap (e.g. parcel), 許す[ゆるす]:to permit|to exempt (from fine)|to confide in|, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
麻衣さんの誤解を解いて
許してもらうしかない》
桜島さん？ 今日は来てないよ｡
え？
Sakurajima-san? She's absent today.
悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
じゃあ その１年の古賀さんが
ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔だったってわけね｡
That means the first-year, Koga-san, was Laplace's demon.
告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional), なくなる:to die, なくなる:to be lost (e.g. luggage)/to be missing|to be used up, 悩む[なやむ]:to be worried/to be troubled, 問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
告白がなくなったことで
古賀を悩ませていた問題は
She avoided being asked out,
and that resolved her immediate problem.
解決[かいけつ]:settlement/solution/resolution
解決したわけだからな｡
何かあったのか？
なんで？
Did something happen?
Why do you ask?
機嫌[きげん]:humour|safety|in a good mood, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
機嫌悪そうだから｡
ﾊｧ…｡
You seem down.
悶々[もんもん]:worrying endlessly/anguishedly
まっ １人で悶々としてるよりは
I guess it'd be better to tell you and make you laugh
instead of keeping it all inside.
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
梓川に話して
笑ってもらったほうがいいか｡
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is, 今朝[けさ, こんちょう]:this morning, 電車[でんしゃ]:train/electric train, 一緒になる[いっしょになる]:to come together/to join
なんだ そりゃ｡
今朝 国見と電車で一緒になった｡
What the heck?
I was on the same train as Kunimi this morning.
それで？
べつに どうも｡
And?
Nothing.
持ち[もち]:hold|wear|usage, 男子[だんし]:youth/young man, 声をかける[こえをかける]:to greet/to call out to someone
彼女持ちの男子に
声をかけられて
I'm just disgusted at myself for being happy when a guy with a girlfriend talked to me.
うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant, 嫌気がさす[いやけがさす]:to be tired of/to be sick of/to get fed up with
うれしいとか思ってる自分に
嫌気がさしてるだけ｡
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is, 乙女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period), チック:cosmetic/stick pomade, 悩み[なやみ]:trouble/troubles/worry
そりゃまた 乙女ﾁｯｸな悩みだな｡
How very girly of you.
声をかける[こえをかける]:to greet/to call out to someone, 虫[むし]:insect/bug/cricket, 走る[はしる]:to run|to travel (movement of vehicles)|to hurry to||
梓川に声をかけられても
虫ずが走るだけなのにね｡
Meanwhile, when you talk to me,
it only makes my skin crawl.
一言[ひとこと, いちげん]:single word/a few words/brief comment, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
その一言 必要だったか？
Did you have to say that part?
ますます:increasingly/more and more/decreasingly (when declining)
なんか私 ますます
ﾀﾞﾒになってるかも｡
I get the feeling I'm getting worse and worse.
いっそ:rather/sooner/preferably
いっそ 言ったらどうだ？
何を？
Why not just tell him?
Tell him what?
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 正論[せいろん]:sound argument/fair argument/just reasoning, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
好きだって｡
今は正論なんて聞きたくない｡
That you like him.
That makes too much sense.
You should clear things up before they get any worse.
以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||, こじらせる:to aggravate/to complicate/to make worse
それ以上こじらせる前に
はっきり:clearly/plainly|to be clear
はっきりさせたほうが
いいと思うぞ｡
告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional), 玉砕[ぎょくさい]:honourable defeat/honorable defeat|trying but being utterly beaten
さっさと告白して 玉砕してこい｡
Tell him how you feel
and have him reject you.
原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source, 悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
それが原因で 私まで
ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔になったら
But what if that turns me
into Laplace's demon too?
収拾[しゅうしゅう]:control/bringing under control/settling (a matter)
梓川は収拾つかなくなるよ｡
You'll go back to square one.
とりあえず:first of all/at once|for now, 昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 脱出[だっしゅつ]:escape/break-out|prolapse
まっ 僕のほうは とりあえず
昨日を脱出できたわけだから
Well, I did manage to get out of yesterday.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, 解く[とく]:to untie|to unsew|to solve||, 解く[ほどく]:to unfasten/to untie/to unwrap (e.g. parcel), 万事[ばんじ]:all/everything, 解決[かいけつ]:settlement/solution/resolution
あとは麻衣さんの誤解さえ解けば
万事解決だけどな｡
Now if I can just clear things up with Mai-san,
everything will be okay.
誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, 解ける[とける]:to be solved|to loosen|to be removed (e.g. restrictions)|, 解ける[ほどける]:to come lose/to come untied|to loosen up (e.g. tension), 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
誤解が解けたら
その前沢って先輩は
But if you clear that up,
won't Maesawa-senpai ask Koga-san out again?
告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
また古賀さんに
告白するんじゃない？
誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, 解ける[とける]:to be solved|to loosen|to be removed (e.g. restrictions)|, 解ける[ほどける]:to come lose/to come untied|to loosen up (e.g. tension), たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
え？
誤解が解けなかったとしても
Even if you don't, he'll notice his misunderstanding soon enough.
勘違い[かんちがい]:misunderstanding/wrong guess, 気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
すぐに勘違いに気づくでしょ｡
そもそも:in the first place/to begin with|... the heck (e.g. "what the heck?"), か月[かげつ]:months (period of), 全校[ぜんこう]:the whole school, 生徒[せいと]:pupil
そもそも梓川は １か月前に
全校生徒の目の前で
You let the entire school know that you love Sakurajima-senpai just a month ago.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
桜島先輩に
告白してるわけなんだし｡
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, やり直し[やりなおし]:redoing
あ… そうなったら また
昨日から やり直し？
Then I'll be thrown back to yesterday again?
可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility, 高い[たかい]:high/tall|expensive
その可能性は高いだろうね｡
That's quite likely.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, つきあい:association/socializing/socialising, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
つまり どうやっても 麻衣さんと
おつきあいできる明日は
So a future where I can go out with Mai-san won't come, no matter what?
状態[じょうたい]:current status/condition/situation
やってこない…｡
梓川 そういう状態を
Azusagawa, do you know what that is called?
なんていうか知ってる？
詰み[つみ]:checkmate
詰みだな｡
Checkmate.
ﾊｧ…｡
どうした？ 咲太｡
What's wrong, Sakuta? Your eyes look dead.
目が死んでるぞ｡
ちょっと ２人ともいいかな？
Got a moment, you two?
もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
今日から
入ってもらうことになった
This is Koga-san. She'll be joining us from today.
フロア:floor, 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
古賀さん｡
ﾌﾛｱの仕事 教えてあげてね｡
Show her the ropes around the floor, will you?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
古賀!?
あっ 先輩！
Koga?
Senpai!
学校[がっこう]:school, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 後輩[こうはい]:junior (at work, school, etc.)/younger people/younger student
あ～ 学校同じ？
それじゃ ﾎﾝﾄの後輩ってことで
Oh, you go to the same school?
Then please look out for her,
as her senior in more ways than one.
いろいろ:various|various colors (colours), 面倒をみる[めんどうをみる]:to care for someone/to look after someone, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
いろいろ面倒をみてあげて｡
よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
こ 古賀朋絵です｡
よろしくお願いします｡
I-I'm Koga Tomoe. Nice to meet you.
俺は 国見佑真｡
そういや 前に
I'm Kunimi Yuuma.
Oh, yeah. Didn't you two kick each other's butts or something?
尻[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 尻[しり]:buttocks|undersurface|last place|, 蹴る[ける]:to kick|to refuse/to reject, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|, 仲[なか]:relation/relationship, 仲[すあい, すわい]:broker/brokerage/brokerage fee
尻を蹴り合った仲とか
言ってたよな｡
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), おもしろい:interesting/fascinating|amusing
なんで人に話すの!?
あんなおもしろいこと
Why are you telling people?!
It'd be a waste to keep
such a funny story to myself.
黙る[だまる]:to be silent, もったい:superior airs/air of importance|overemphasis
黙ってたら もったいないだろ｡
Azusagawa-kun.
番[ばん]:number (in a series)|(one's) turn|watch|, 番[つがい]:(one) pair (e.g. of birds)/brace|joint, テーブル:table, オーダー:order, お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
梓川くん ７番ﾃｰﾌﾞﾙ ｵｰﾀﾞｰお願い｡
Take Table 7's order, please.
On it.
わかりました｡
...I hear.
らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
(亜矢)らしくてさ｡
(日南子)えっ そうなの？
What? Really?
注文[ちゅうもん]:order/request, 注文[ちゅうぶん]:annotation/explanatory note, 決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
(玲奈)だから来たんでしょ｡
ご注文は お決まりですか？
That's why we're here.
Are you ready to order?
本気[ほんき]:seriousness/earnestness/truth
あ？
朋絵のこと 本気なんですか？
Do you really have feelings for Tomoe?
当店[とうてん]:this store
すみません 当店では
ﾄﾓｴﾉｺﾄ ﾎﾝｷﾅﾝﾃﾞｽｶは
I'm sorry. "Do you really have feelings for Tomoe" is not on our menu.
扱う[あつかう]:to deal with (a person)|to deal with (a problem)|to operate (e.g. a machine)||, まじめ:diligent/serious/honest
扱っていないもので｡
まじめに聞いてるんですけど！
I'm asking a serious question here!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
(亜矢)桜島先輩にふられて
すぐだから 心配してるんです｡
We're worried because it happened soon after you got rejected by Sakurajima-senpai.
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken
(日南子)朋絵 確かにかわいいけど
どこがよかったんですか？
Sure, Tomoe's really cute,
but what else do you like about her?
勘違い[かんちがい]:misunderstanding/wrong guess, たぶん:informing, たぶん:perhaps/probably|generous
なんか勘違いしてるぞ たぶん｡
You seem to have the wrong idea about something.
You don't have to hide it. We already know.
隠す[かくす]:to hide/to conceal
隠さなくても もう知ってますよ｡
あっ 朋絵 いたよ｡
There's Tomoe.
やっほ～｡
Yoohoo.
Rena-chan, you guys! You really made it!
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
玲奈ちゃん みんなも｡
ﾎﾝﾄに来てくれたの？
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, じゃん:isn't it, 制服[せいふく]:uniform
絶対に行くって言ったじゃん｡
制服かわいい｡
We did promise to come.
That's a cute uniform.
うん かわいい｡
Yeah, you look great.
Senpai, if you're just messing around with Tomoe, you'll have hell to pay.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 遊び[あそび]:playing|play (margin between on and off, gap before pressing button or lever has an effect), 許す[ゆるす]:to permit|to exempt (from fine)|to confide in|
先輩 朋絵のこと遊びなら
許しませんよ｡
Senpai, I need a favor!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please, 断る[ことわる]:to refuse|to inform|to ask leave
先輩 実は先輩にお願いが！
断る｡
I refuse.
せめて:at least/at most, せめて:offense/offence/method of attack, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 断る[ことわる]:to refuse|to inform|to ask leave
せめて話を聞いてよ｡
聞くのを断る｡
At least hear me out!
I refuse to listen.
大方[おおかた]:large part|people in general|mostly|
なしてぇ？
大方 僕と古賀が
But why?
You want me to keep quiet and let people think that you and I are dating, right?
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target, 誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding
つきあってる的な誤解を
そのままにしてほしいとか
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
言うんだろ？
先輩 心が読めるとね!?
Are ya a mind reader?!
Don't you have other things to worry about?
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 気にする[きにする]:to mind (negative nuance)/to care about/to worry, ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
てか もっと
気にすることがあるだろ｡
思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty, 症候群[しょうこうぐん]:syndrome
思春期症候群のこと｡
それは 今日になったから
Like your Puberty Syndrome?
We made it to today,
so that doesn't matter anymore.
じゃん:isn't it, どころ:particle used to indicate that what precedes it is an extreme example and strongly negates it
もういいじゃん｡
今は それどころじゃないの｡
I've got bigger problems now! I'm in big trouble!
ピンチ:crisis/tough spot/predicament, だいたい:outline/main point|general, だいたい:battalion, 誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding
ﾋﾟﾝﾁなの！
だいたい誤解をそのままにって
How long do you want me to let people have the wrong idea, anyway?
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year, 卒業[そつぎょう]:graduation/completion (e.g. of a course)|outgrowing something
いつまでだよ｡ まさか
３年生が卒業するまでか？
Surely not until the third-years graduate?
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
そこは ちゃんと考えてきたよ｡
I do have a plan for that.
誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something, 学期[がっき]:school term/semester, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
誤解してもらうのは
１学期の間だけだから｡ お願い！
They just have to think we're dating until first term ends, so please!
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 学校[がっこう]:school
夏休みになっちゃえば
学校もないし
There won't be any school over summer break,
間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||, うやむや:indefinite/hazy/vague, ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that
その間に関係が
うやむやになったことにすれば
so we can say things fell apart then.
学期[がっき]:school term/semester, 普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train
２学期は 普通にできるでしょ？
ﾊｧ…｡
That way, we can go back to normal in second term.
Hey, Senpai!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
ねぇ 先輩！
学校[がっこう]:school, 内[うち]:inside|while|among||, 内[ない]:inside/within, 評判[ひょうばん]:fame/reputation|rumour (rumor), 最悪[さいあく]:the worst|in the worst case
自分で言うのもなんだけど
学校内の評判が最悪な僕と
I know I'm not one to talk,
but do you really wanna pretend-date
the guy with the worst reputation in school?
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target, ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that
つきあってる的なことにするのは
いいのか？
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room
最近の先輩 １年生の間じゃ
Actually, you've gone full circle and reached dateable status among the first-years lately.
周[しゅう]:Zhou (dynasty of China)|perimeter|counter for laps or circuits, 回る[めぐる]:to go around|to return|to surround|, 回る[まわる]:to turn|to visit several places|to function well|, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
１周回って
ｱﾘってことになってるから
平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right, そりゃ:very/extremely|that is
平気だと思う｡
なんだ そりゃ｡
I think it'll be fine.
What the hell?
グラウンド:sports ground/sports oval, 中心[ちゅうしん]:center/centre|-centered, 中心[なかご]:core|tang (of a sword, etc.)|middle of a nest of boxes, 愛[あい]:love/affection|attachment, 愛[まな]:beloved/dear, 叫ぶ[さけぶ]:to shout/to cry|to clamor (for or against), なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train
ｸﾞﾗｳﾝﾄﾞの中心で愛を叫ぶなんて
普通 ありえないし｡
It's not every day that a guy screams about
his love in the center of the school ground.
憧れる[あこがれる]:to long for/to yearn after/to admire
ああいうの ちょっと憧れる｡
It's kinda sweet.
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness
古賀には 絶対しないけどな｡
ん～｡
I'd never do that for you.
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, 急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time)
あっそうだ つきあってるだと
急すぎるから
Oh, right.
It'd be too sudden to say we're dating,
so let's go with something more gradual.
手前[てまえ]:before|one's standpoint|we|, 手前[てめえ]:you (used by young males)|oneself, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
その手前くらいがいいな｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||, 恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart, 未満[みまん]:less than/insufficient, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target
先輩以上恋人未満的な？
Like, "more than schoolmates, less than lovers"?
お前さ 自分が
何をしようとしているか
Look, do you realize what you're trying to do?
全校[ぜんこう]:the whole school, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, つくる:to make/to produce|to prepare (food)
わかってるのか？ 全校生徒に
ｳｿをつくってことだぞ｡
You'll be lying to the entire school, you know?
I know that.
お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
わかってるよ そんなこと｡
とにかく お願い！
Please just help me.
I lived in Fukuoka until middle school.
中学[ちゅうがく]:middle school/junior high school, 福岡[ふくおか]:Fukuoka (city)
私 中学までは福岡で
高校[こうこう]:senior high school/high school, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
こっちには
高校からの友達しかいないの｡
My friends from high school
are the only ones I have here.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill
さっきの３人か｡
そう｡
Those three earlier?
Yeah.
And if I don't do something,
I'll become the class outcast.
クラス:class, 居場所[いばしょ]:whereabouts/place|place where one belongs, なくなる:to die, なくなる:to be lost (e.g. luggage)/to be missing|to be used up
このままだと 私 ｸﾗｽに
居場所なくなっちゃう｡
休み時間[やすみじかん]:recess/break time/break between classes, ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal, お弁当[おべんとう]:bento/Japanese box lunch, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
休み時間も ひとりで
お弁当も ひとりで食べて
I'll be alone during recess and have to eat alone.
トイレ:toilet/restroom/bathroom, ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
ﾄｲﾚも ひとりで行くのは嫌｡
I don't wanna go to the washroom alone either.
Please go to the washroom alone.
トイレ:toilet/restroom/bathroom, ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal, 無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||
ﾄｲﾚは ひとりで行けよ｡
無理｡
No way.
ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal, 楽[らく]:comfort/ease|raku pottery
ひとりはひとりで楽だぞ｡
Being alone has its benefits, you know.
周囲[しゅうい]:surroundings/environs|circumference, 合わせる[あわせる]:to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)|to join together|to face||, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
周囲に合わせる必要ないし
You don't have to try to fit in,
寂しい[さびしい, さみしい]:lonely/lonesome/solitary, 感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense
なってみれば 思ったほど
寂しいとは感じない｡
and it's not as lonely as you'd think.
寂しい[さびしい, さみしい]:lonely/lonesome/solitary, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
べつに寂しいから
嫌なわけじゃないし｡
It's not like I'm worried about being lonely.
はぁ？ なら なんだよ？
What? Then what's the problem?
ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal, 恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
ひとりは… 恥ずかしい｡
Being alone is shameful.
ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal
みんなから ｱｲﾂ
いつもひとりだって
I don't want people looking at me and going,
"Oh, she's always alone."
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
思われるのは 嫌｡
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant, 学校[がっこう]:school, 恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
⦅嫌… 学校行くの恥ずかしい⦆
No...
I'm too ashamed to go to school.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
先輩？
わかった｡
Senpai?
Okay, fine.
全校[ぜんこう]:the whole school, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, ウソをつく:to tell a lie/to fib, ホント:truth/reality/actuality
全校生徒にｳｿをついてやるよ｡
ﾎﾝﾄに!?
I'll lie to the entire school for you.
Really?
一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
ああ｡
それじゃ もう一つお願い｡
Yeah.
In that case, I have one more favor to ask.
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, バイト:work (esp. part time or casual), 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
あ 明日なんだけど
先輩 ﾊﾞｲﾄ終わったあと ﾃﾞ ﾃﾞ…｡
T-Tomorrow, after you're done with work...
D-D-D...
デコピン:poke in the forehead
ﾃﾞｺﾋﾟﾝだな｡
違う！
Ding your forehead?
No!
Go on a d-date with me!
デート:date/go on a date
ﾃﾞ ﾃﾞｰﾄして！
なぜだ？
Why?
デート:date/go on a date
玲奈ちゃんに ｢ﾃﾞｰﾄはしないの？｣
って聞かれて｡
Rena-chan asked me if we're not going to go on dates or anything.
Just lie to her and say you had a great time
over the weekend or something.
適当[てきとう]:suitable/proper|noncommittal, 週末[しゅうまつ]:weekend, ハッスル:hustle
そんなの適当に ｢あ～ 週末は
ﾊｯｽﾙした！｣ って
ごまかす:to deceive/to falsify|to dodge, 念[ねん]:sense|desire|attention, 写真を撮る[しゃしんをとる]:to take a picture
ごまかせばいいだろ｡
念のため 写真を撮っておきたい｡
I wanna take pictures, just in case she asks.
意外[いがい]:unexpected/surprising, ぬかり:blunder/miss/slip
お前 意外と ぬかりないな｡
Wow, you're surprisingly thorough.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 伝える[つたえる]:to convey/to report/to transmit
《麻衣さんには
どう伝えたものか…｡
What am I supposed to tell Mai-san?
きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 必死[ひっし]:frantic|inevitable death|brinkmate (inevitable checkmate), 弁解[べんかい]:explanation (e.g. for one's actions)/excuse/justification
きっと必死に弁解する僕を見て
I bet she'll smile happily as I grovel before her.
心底[しんそこ, しんてい]:bottom of one's heart/depths of one's mind|completely (from the bottom of one's heart), 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|
心底楽しそうに笑うだろうな…》
Damn, that sounds fun.
やばい:dangerous/risky|awful, やばい:wild Japanese apricot, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
やべえ すげえ楽しそう｡
As the last week of June draws to a close, a hot summer is right around the corner.
テレビ:television/TV, 今週[こんしゅう]:this week, 終わり[おわり]:the end
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]さて ６月も今週で終わり
そろそろ:slowly/quietly|soon, 暑い[あつい]:hot (weather, etc.)/warm, 季節[きせつ]:season, 天気[てんき]:weather/the elements|fair weather, コマーシャル:commercial (e.g. TV)
そろそろ暑い季節がやってきます｡
お天気はｺﾏｰｼｬﾙのあと
Stick around, because after this break,
Sakiyama-san will have the forecast for us.
気象予報士[きしょうよほうし]:weather forecaster, 詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well, 解説[かいせつ]:explanation/commentary/exposition
気象予報士の咲山さんが
詳しく解説します｡
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
あっ お兄ちゃん この人
Look, Onii-chan! Isn't that the girl you brought home before?
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 連れる[つれる]:to lead/to take (a person)
前に お兄ちゃんが
連れてきた人ですよね？
一口[ひとくち]:mouthful|gulp|one word|, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
一口あげよっか？
Want a sip?
やっぱ:too/also|still
やっぱﾀﾞﾒ！
Actually, I changed my mind.
Yeah, that's her.
ああ そうだな｡
(ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝ)
Who is it, so late at night?
なんだ？ こんな時間に｡
はい｡
Yes?
It's me.
私｡
言い訳[いいわけ]:excuse|explanation
どうして 言い訳しに来ないのよ？
Why won't you come explain yourself to me?
That's Azusagawa for you. Filthy pig.
Next Episode
#5: Wishing You All the Lies in the World